A Guide to the Virginia Convention of 1776 General Correspondence, Minutes, and Journals, 1774-1776
Library of Virginia
- Series I: Papers, 1774-1776., Extent: 2.45 cu. ft. (8 boxes). (Box 1-6 (Boxes 1, 1a, 2-4, 4a, 5-6))
  - Report of the Committee of Caroline County,, 1776 May 31 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - Report of the Committee of Spotsylvania County, 1776 May 31 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - Letter of Robert Howe, Halifax, to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 May 31 (laid before the Convention) (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - Draft resolutions regarding Governor Eden of Maryland, 1776 May 31 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - Fragments, 1776 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Petition of inhabitants west of Laurel Hill (Pa.-Va. boundary), 1776 June 1 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Resolution regarding ammunition, 1776 June 1 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Letter of Capt. Gregory Smith to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 June 2 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Letter of Charles Lee, Tarborough, to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 June 3 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Draft resolution regarding cadets, 1776 June 4 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Order regarding David Ross, 1776 June 6 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Report of Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding James Walker, 1776 June 7 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Letter of Brig. Gen. Andrew Lewis to the Convention, 1776 June 7 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Depositions regarding George Oldner, 1776 June 7 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Letter of George Oldner to Committee of Safety,, 1776 June 7 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Proceedings of a Court of Inquiry, 1776 June 7 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - List of prisoners brought to Williamsburg, 1776 June 7 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Petition of inhabitants of Loudoun County, 1776 June 8 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Letter of John Carmount to the Convention, 1776 June 8 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Petition of Thomas Potter, 1776 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Petition of Manasses McGahey, 1776 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Papers regarding Robert Shedden, 1776 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Petition of inhabitants of Newport Parish (Isle of Wight Co., Va.), 1776 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Petition of John Goodrich, Sr., ca. 1776 June 10 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Depositions of James Buchanan and James Anderson, 1776 June 11 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Draft order regarding Charles Neilson, 1776 June 11 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Letter of John Dunlop to John Blair, 1776 June 11 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Petition of owners of Gingoteague Island (Accomack Co., Va.), 1776 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Petition of freeholders of Spotsylvania County, 1776 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Draft resolution regarding the pardon of Harbakkuk Pride, Samuel Flanagin, and Manasses McGahey, 1776 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Resolution appropriating money for support of the troops, 1776 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Proposed amendments to the Declaration of Rights, 1776 June 12 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Letter of James Robinson to John Blair, 1776 June 13 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Order of Edmund Pendleton to the sheriff of King William County, 1776 June 13 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Report of the Committee on Public Claims, 1776 June 14 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding certification of election of delegates, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Certificates of election made in form prescribed by the ordinance, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Certificates of election not made in form prescribed by the ordinance, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Petition of Wilson Miles Cary, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Petition of James Johnson, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Petition of inhabitants of Stratton Major Parish (King and Queen Co., Va.), 1776 June 15 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding sundry petitions (Amelia, Caroline, Chesterfield, Lunenburg, and Mecklenburg Counties, Va.), 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding the Chesterfield County petition, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Draft ordinance to amend an ordinance for raising and embodying a sufficient force for the defence and protection of the Colony, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding John Ballendine's petition, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Ordinance for making farther provision for the defense of the Colony, 1776 June 19 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Treaty between the Chiefs of the Cherokee Nation and John Stuart, 1776 June 15 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Resolution regarding Pennsylvania-Virginia boundary, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Draft report of the Committee of Public Claims regarding John Harvie and Joseph Neaville, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Resolution regarding hospital for wounded at Williamsburg, 1776 June 15 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Resolution regarding the formation of a board to direct naval affairs, 1776 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Resolution to appoint persons to examine the navigable rivers of the Colony and a list of commissioners, 1776 June 17 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Report of the Committee of Public Claims regarding the petitions of George Moffitt and others, 1776 June 19 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Petition of members of the Baptist Church at Occoquan (Prince William Co., Va.), 1776 June 20 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Opinion of the Committee of Safety regarding Scotch prisoners, 1776 June 22 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding William Christian and Arthur Campbell, 1776 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Ordinance to amend an ordinance entitled an ordinance to provide for paying the expenses of the delegates from this Colony to the General Congress, 1776 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Resolution for temporary provisions for the administration of justice, 1776 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - Resolution regarding the disposal of property of Lord Dunmore in Hampshire County, 1776 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Ordinance for establishing a Board of Commissioners to superintend and direct the naval affairs of this colony, 1776 June 22 (Box 6, Folder 54a)
  - Report of the Committee of Public Claims, 1776 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Resolution regarding claims to Indian lands, 1776 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Report of the Committee of Public claims regarding Capt. Joseph Haynes and others, 1776 June 24 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Resolution regarding gaming, 1776 June 25 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Writ of election for Culpeper County, 1776 June 25 (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - Report of the committee to consider the reports of the Committee of Caroline and Spotsylvania Counties (Va.), 1776 June 26 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - Resolution regarding tobacco warehouses, 1776 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - Ordinance to enable the present magistrates to continue the administration of justice, 1776 June 27 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - Journal of proceedings of a company commanded by Capt. John Shelby to Nanachuckie against the Tories and other enemies to America, 1776 June 28 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Letter of Capt. John Neville (Ft. Pitt), 1776 June 29 (laid before the Convention) (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - Unidentified, undated (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - Fragments, undated (Box 6, Folder 66)
- Series II: Oversize Papers, 1774-1776., Extent: .75 cu. ft. (1 box). (Box 7)
  - Petition of James Fazakerley, 1775 March (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Instruction of the Committee of Norfolk Borough to their delegates regarding grain, 1775 July 28 (Box 7, Folder 1a)
  - Ordinance for appointing commissioners to settle accounts of the militia, 1775 August 12 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Ordinance for regulating election of delegates, 1775 August 12 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Petition of the inhabitants and freeholders of Chesterfield County, 1775 August 20 (Box 7, Folder 3a)
  - Report of a committee appointed to prepare a plan for embodying and disciplining a militia, 1775 March 25 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Petition of merchants and traders of the Borough of Norfolk and Town of Portsmouth, 1775 August 1 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Letter of W.R.W. Curle to the Chairman of the Committee at Williamsburg, 1775 August 11 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Petition of the committee of Accomack County, 1775 November 30 (Box 7, Folder 6a)
  - Advertisement for Transylvania Company (part of Transylvania papers), 1775 December 1 (Box 7, Folder 6b)
  - Papers (intercepted letters), 1775 December 5 (Box 7, Folder 6c)
  - Papers (intercepted letters), Letter from Samuel Elam [1775 August 7], 1775 December 6 (Box 7, Folder 6d)
  - Petition of Archibald Camptell, 1775 December 16 (Box 7, Folder 6e)
  - Amendments to the ordinance for raising a number of forces for the defense of the colony, 1775 December 21 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Letter of Ralph Wormeley, Jr., to John Grymes, 1776 April 4 (Box 7, Folder 7a)
  - Petition of Arthur Upshur (Accomack Co., Va.), 1776 April 25 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Petition of the committee of Norfolk County, 1776 May 6 (Box 7, Folder 8a)
  - Petition of the inhabitants of Lunenburg County (Va.), 1776 May 11 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Resolution of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the election of delegates from King William County, 1776 May 18 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Petition of the inhabitants of Mecklenburg County (Va.), 1776 May 20 (Box 7, Folder 10a)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding the petition of John Ballendine and John Reveley, 1776 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding the qualifications of Gabriel Penn, 1776 May 22 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Letter of Charles Lee (Halifax Co., Va.) to Edmund Pendleton, 1776 May 24 (Box 7, Folder 12a)
  - Draft ordinance for augmenting the Ninth Regiment of Regular Forces, 1776 May 25 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Petition of the inhabitants and freeholders of Norfolk County, 1776 May 28 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding Joshua Hopkins, Peter Butt, and Henry Hambleton, 1776 May 28 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Resolution instructing the Committee of Safety to write a letter to the President of the Convention of Maryland regarding Governor Eden, 1776 May 31 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Report of the Committee appointed to prepare a bill to encourage the making of salt, salt petre, and gunpowder, 1776 June (ca.) (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Petition of the inhabitants of Port Royal and the counties of King George, Caroline, and Westmoreland Counties (Va.), 1776 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Petition of sundry assistants to merchants and other natives of Great Britain, 1776 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 18a)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding Thomas Mitchell, 1776 June 1 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Petition of offiers and soldiers of Amelia County (Va.), 1776 June 4 (Box 7, Folder 19a)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding John McIntire, Alexander Thompson, George Older, William Ancock, and Stephen Sampson, 1776 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Report of the Committee to inquire into the state of prisoners in the Public Gaol, 1776 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding certain slaves in the Public Gaol, 1776 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Petition of William Aylett, 1776 June 7 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding Robert Shedden, 1776 June 10 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding John Goodrich, 1776 June 11 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Report of the Committee appointed to enquire into the services of persons appointed to fill up the Treasury notes, 1776 June 10 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Confession of John Goodrich, 1776 June 11 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Report of the Committee to inquire into the offenses of several criminals confined in the Public Gaol, 1776 June 11 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Report of the Committee of Privileges and Elections regarding Charles Henley, 1776 June 11 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Ordinance to supply certain defects in a former ordinance of this Convention for raising six troops of horse, 1776 June 19 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Constitution (photostat), 1776 June 24 (Box 7, Folder 30a)
  - Ordinance for erecting salt works in this Colony and for encouraging the making of salt, 1776 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Report of the Committee of Propositions and Grievances regarding the petition of sundry natives of Great Britain, 1776 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Amendments to the Constitution of the state of Virginia, 1776 June 28 (Box 7, Folder 33)